all right another Moscone example versus
Justin Bergman and Europe was up 9 to 6
here and I'm down 4 to 3
so a pretty big match here because they
put up Shane after Justin so they were
thinking of Justin wins this match it's
9 7 then Shane wins 9 8
so was pressure on me right I knew I
beat Justin before in this tournament so
my team was hoping that I would beat him
again so was I of course I've come up
with a dry break and of course I'm down
I should've shaved for that day I can
see but just again the mental side of
this rack guys I'm under the gun
Justin has full initiative of this rack
and match because he could put me in a
tough spot here he can't make any balls
but he can really play a good safety
let's see what he does and I'm hoping
for a chance and an inning at the table
to do whatever I can stick with it and
try to regain initiative a lot of times
it's about attitude guys things are not
working for you stick with it it can
change at any second
so Justin try to use the 2 and the 6
there to give me a really tough kick I
can still see this one I'm trying to
bank it towards the left side of the
table and also use the 2 and 6 as
blockers so I need to put a lot of right
spin on this ball to make it pass the
six ball otherwise it's gonna hit the
ball and at the same time I don't want a
lot of movement on my cue ball so very
tough shot to execute shot clock
and actually I get a little bit
fortunate but also some bad luck in the
same shot I actually make this bank but
the cue ball gets too far on the short
rail and now I'm really in a tough spot
guys he's up for three seas wipe in the
towel he's looking at his fans like I'm
gonna get a chance here and once again
this is attitude I have to do whatever I
can do to stick with it boom also an
example of how to deal with the shot
clock the shot clock will force you to
let your intuition take over on occasion
because if you're in trouble and there's
no time the only thing you have is your
experience your intuition and all those
years that you have played the game so
here also I have no time I have to go
make the three tough shot that was now
I'm I'm a little bit over this eight
ball with the cue ball that's why I'm my
face has shown some expression but
because I cannot draw it back I have to
roll it and I'm thinking okay I can just
hit the left side of the cue ball so I'm
gonna try to cross over to the other
side and play the five in the side
pocket
there so again not the greatest of angle
I have to draw the ball in cue ball has
a chance to go towards the left side
pocket I still have to getting in good
line here but mentally I'm just letting
my intuition do all the talking here I
have no more time to go over some nice
options or anything
now of course I'm in good line again and
I can start breathing a little bit
easier and try to close it out to make
it four four and what you also see guys
that sometimes if you think things
weren't going well right the other
player had the initiative now what's
happening I'm reversing the pressure
Justin has been sitting in the chair now
looking at a couple of crazy shots he
had the initiative of this match and now
it's four four and the pressures on in
on him and luckily for me he made a
mistake in the final game I got to close
it out and score the point for our team
so even when things seem hopeless there
for a little while stick with it guys
it's all about attitude in this next
example we're looking at a match that I
played against Mike Dechaine at the
Mosconi Cup
it's the third match of the event I was
up on my in my first singles match of
this event and this is just an example
of when you've done a lot of hard work
I prepared really well for this one and
is to show you the focus that I had in
this game the level of focus that's what
I want to show you I did a lot of good
solid mental work had a good streak of
meditation I was really clear in my mind
and I just want to show you the focus
that I have gone through this rack it's
a little bit of a tricky rack right
we've only played the five on five up to
this point so we didn't get much table
time yet the nerves are there the speed
of the table is still a little bit to be
discovered it's always a little bit
different big crowds you made it the new
cloth different table brands and the
other years and I just want to show you
the focus and the reward that I give
myself practically for doing the hard
work before the tournament my body's
really relaxed that's what we go through
in the course right a relaxed body and a
super sharp focused mind that's the
combination that you need for playing
your best ball it's got to be balanced
and sometimes you're a little bit too
hyped or sometimes you're a little bit
too unfocused so it's not easy to find
this crystal clear balance but when it's
there you have to cherish it and that's
what I'm doing in this rack right a
little bit of tricky positions I have to
get above this five ball to get back
down for the six ball and the table so
fast I'm a little bit afraid of just
slow rolling it so I'm going off the
rail but again my mind's working well
see I see the traps my intuition is
really clicking well
and I'm five balls away from running
this racket tying up the game bake point
in the Mosconi cup day one but I'm down
to one in this match so if I don't get
out here then it's gonna be three one
two Mike and that could mean that USA's
got their first point on the board
two-to-one if I do get out here it's 2-2
now Mike's gonna feel some pressure
again and if I can take this match or up
3 to 0 and a 1 that's like an amazing
start of course for a team so once again
I'm starting to click with my position
plate it's falling it's coming together
very nicely
2 balls away from running this rack and
it's just a nice example of giving
myself that reward for all the hard work
right mentally everything's nice
my body's nice and relaxed so that's
what you get there you go 2 2 2
[Music]
[Applause]
now win deathmatch and we get ahead
three to nothing
[Music]